# Vamsi Karuturi

krishnavamsikaruturi8@gmail.com | Mobile: 778-057-0356 || linkedin.com/in/vamsi-karuturi | github.com/vamsi1998123

#### Summary

Software Engineer dedicated to continuous improvement with over 3+ years of experience as a Java Full Stack Developer. Successfully designed and implemented complex software programs increasing the efficiency by 60%. Proponent of observational learning, drawing insights from colleagues, peers, and learned experiences. Committed to Agile Methodology for efficient project delivery.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Software Development Engineer

November 2022 - Present

Siemens

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Engaged in the development of SINEC AMS, addressing network complexity in the digital age to streamlined management and peak performance, contributing to a 60% increase in overall efficiency.
- Transformed a large-scale distributed industrial network management product, boosting availability by over 85%, which led to increased operational efficiency and minimized downtime for critical systems.
- Pioneered the implementation of Test-Driven Development (TDD) methodology, resulting in a remarkable 25% reduction in code defects. This initiative not only improved software reliability and performance but also accelerated development cycles, delivering products faster and more reliably.
- Engineered a high-performance MicroService utilizing Neo4j Graph DB technology to optimize network planning by 70% and increase in scalability.
- Integrated advanced features and use cases that contributed to a 50% reduction in network latency.
- Implemented Caching and Multi-Tenancy mechanisms which reduced the latency by 60%.

### Senior Analyst

December 2020 - November 2022

Capqemini

Huderabad, Telangana

- Orchestrated the design and successful implementation of Advanced Modelling Platform, promptly resolving 95 assigned bugs, reducing billing errors by 30% and enhancing customer satisfaction by 25%.
- Developed and deployed 250 lock check rules Feature within a span of 2 months, contributing significantly to system efficiency using AWS and improving customer satisfaction.
- Empowered and mentored 4 co-workers and junior developers, fostering a collaborative and growth-oriented work environment.
- Delivered Integration User Stories in collaboration with other teams within a tight timeline of 2 months, ensuring seamless system integration.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Expertise in Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Technologies: Core Java, Java 8, Java 17, J2EE, Spring Framework, MultiThreading, Spring Boot, Rest API's, PostgreSQL, MySQL, JUnit, Mockito, Angular, Hibernate, JPA, Microservices, TDD, Design Patterns, Solid Principles, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, CI/CD
- Tools: Maven, Git, Eclipse, IntelliJ Idea, Postman, Agile Methodology

#### ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Recognized as a Star Performer at Siemens in February 2023 for consistent exceptional results.
- Delivery Excellence Award: Awarded for the extraordinary technical contributions towards AMP Product in 2021.

#### EDUCATION

# Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering

July 2017 - September 2020

VNR Vignana Jyothi Institute of Engineering and Technology

# Interests

You (III)

Refresh Java By Sai Karuturi: Created videos on Java and Web-development.

medium.com/@krishnavamsikaruturi8: Sharing technical knowledge in the continuously growing group.